

ln: linkedin.com/in/hngy/

e: h.yu@hchy.tw

# **HENG YU**

» Heng Yu is an architect, designer, and filmmaker enthusiastic about exploring various physical and digital tools that facilitate architecture as a medium to exchange and communicate design thinking. He first participated in mid to large-scale building projects in Taiwan, where he worked with external/internal groups of professionals from various disciplines and became proficient in collaborating and coordinating. During his time in the Berlage, he took the leading role in the collective video production. In 2022, he subsequently worked on the exhibition filmography for IABR: Future Generation and assisted in coordinating an urban design competition for KCAP. In 2023, he co-started the design office HCHY, whose works span across Taiwan and the Netherlands. His diverse experiences offer a blend of aesthetics and interdisciplinary insight.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

2023-present

### HCHY | 3D visualiser

Taichung, Taiwan / Rotterdam, the Netherlands

- » Produce short films for competition entries in Taiwan, and
- » create renderings for interior design project in Taichung, Rotterdam and Brussels.

### 2022 KCAP | Urban Designer

Rotterdam, the Netherlands

- $^{\mathrm{w}}$  Contributed to project management for an urban design competition of 28 km2,
- » internal coordination with local and international teams on technical deliverables,
- » consolidated inputs from external disciplines of ecology, hydrology, and transportation in the development of masterplan project of 28 km2, and
- » delivered diagrams/drawings to facilitate design development and presentation.

### 2018-2020

### L. R. Hsiao Architect & Associates | Junior Architect

Taipei, Taiwan

- » Conducted preliminary research and design of large scale public buildings,
- » applied building permit and examined compliance with regulations,
- » drafted detailed design drawings, and
- » contributed to the design development of building projects in close collaboration with external/internal disciplines of electrical technicians, infrastructural engineers (for building integration with subway stations), and sustainability specialists.

### 2016-2017

# G. H. Li Architect & Associates | Designer

Tainan, Taiwan

- » Drafted design concept diagram in mid-scale public buildings,
- » built physical models of public and private building designs, and
- » visualised and delivered 3D rendering of building designs/presentations.

## <sup>2014</sup> Yasutaka Yoshimura Architect| Intern

Tokyo, Japan

- » Translated and examined compliance with regulation for a project in Taipei, and
- » built study models for appearance study and construction details

### **EDUCATION**

### 2020-2022 Technische Universiteit Delft

Delft. the Netherlands

» Master of Science in the Berlage Post-master in Architecture and Urban Design

# 2011-2017 National Cheng Kung University

Tainan, Taiwan

» Bachelor of Architecture at the Department of Architecture

### **SELECTED FILM WORKS**

#### 2023-present Short Films for Competitions and Projects

www.youtube.com/@hchytw

» A short film selection for professional works

#### 2024 Housing in Doubt | E0. Closing Statement

vimeo.com/1007352774

- » A short film documented the anti-squatting housing model in the Netherlands
- » A work with Jin Young Chang and Midas Hoezen

#### 2023 Dériville

vimeo.com/837100175

- » A vitual walk-through in the city center of Madrid, Spain
- » Project proposal for 23/24 Medialab Matadero Madrid

#### 2022 IABR: Future Generation

- » Exhibition Filmography, IABR
- » A work with Juan Benavides

#### 2022 Aardkt

vimeo.com/670615254

- » A animation of a day's journey of Dutch potatoes through the proposed auction market
- » A Project Thesis, the Berlage

# <sup>2022</sup> Supermarket

vimeo.com/670611424

- » A video essay and project proposal of the food industry in the Netherlands and beyond
- » Collective video for Project Thesis, the Berlage

#### 2021 Welcome to Albert Heijn: an Annotated Analysis

vimeo.com/696200379/ccae5011db

- A annotated analysis of an Albert Heijn branch in Delft
- » Collective research video for Thesis Development, the Berlage

#### 2021 Cybernetic TV

vimeo.com/566302067/9f52331532

- » A video essay on national propaganda disguised as a media event
- » Space, TV, and Architecture (seminar led by Léa-Catherine Szacka), the Berlage

#### 2021 Living in a Sandcastle

vimeo.com/540644886

- » A kaleidoscopic array of slides of detailed domestic memories
- » A Journey Round My Room (master class led by Bêka & Lemoine), the Berlage

#### 2020 All Watched by Machines of Loving Grace

vimeo.com/504543105

- » A video essay on the digital infrastructure in the Netherlands
- » Project NL, the Berlage

#### 2014 Tainan China Town

vimeo.com/117096010

- » A documentary of a soon-to-be-demolished builling in Tainan, Taiwan
- » Documentary Making, NCKU

### **SKILLS**

software

» Madarin (native speaker) language

» adobe creative suite

- » archicad
- » autocad

- » English (C1 level)
- » blender
- » qgis
- » processing / P5.js
- » Dutch (A2 level)
- » rhinoceros (grasshopper)
- » unity